Where's the head. Gary?
Someone's been down there. Gary.
Anything on the soil
in McGee's ute?
That's at the bottom
of my list.
Jonas McGee.
He was strangled to death.
The beheading... Came after.
I don't know where
Jonas was getting his black from.
but it was definitely not
down that mine.
So this is Kalingra.
Nobody works here.
That woman was
in Robbie Inglis's car.
It was like she was a different
person. but that's her.
Get her on the hook.
She's so close.
I can feel it.
You buried him
because he had what you wanted.
And eunuchs who have
made themselves so for the sake
of the kingdom of heaven.
You do me a favour.
Next time you talk to Phelan.
why don't you tell him I said hello?
Destroying key evidence
in a murder investigation.
Patricia. Patricia.
You're playing with fire.
And now for tonight's
headline act.
A man who always reads the room just
a little too late.
A man who trusts first
and thinks second.
Ooh!
Your favourite lone ranger.
Detective Ivan Lucic!
But tonight he's met his match.
She'll stab you in the back
and smile while she does it.
Please welcome
Detective Nell Buchanan.
Where is my phone?
Ivan. are you OK?
Oh.
Did you lose your special
coin again?
Oh.
Did you lose your special boy again?
Shut up. Dazzler!
The mayor's dead.
He's gone.
-How long was he in the tub?
-Five. maybe six hours.
Yeah. we had to fish him out.
He was looking like a steamed
dim sim.
That's lunch ruined.
All right. well. I'll get him back
to the morgue. do the autopsy.
Gary. can you take Frank
for some fresh air?
Yes. sir. Yes. sir.
Three bags full. sir.
Detectives.
Please.
Sit.
Thank you for coming.
What a way to go. eh?
He loved that spa.
It was his safe place.
And yet...
I told him not to keep the blender
so close.
But...
..that was my Dougie.
Always living life on the edge.
Right. Pat?
Yeah.
Best ones always do.
Lydia. Mrs Mayor.
When was the last
time you saw your husband alive?
It was after you left.
I went to bed to get my beauty
sleep. and he decided to stay up.
He wanted to look at the stars.
Any other visitors?
Detective. Please don't.
This wasn't foul play. This...
My husband was loved.
This was a cruel accident.
Nothing else.
An accident.
Darling.
This town doesn't do subtle.
If someone wanted him dead.
we'd know about it. wouldn't we.
Pat?
Yeah.
Nice touch.
The statue.
It's important for continuity.
So this hasn't got anything to do
with your case.
No?
Why don't you just let the poor
woman grieve?
Condolences.
No foul play. my arse.
Are you here for the
decapitation or the castration?
Welcome to Nulla.
I'm the airport manager. Yuri Sidov.
Detective Senior Sergeant Phelan.
Is it always like this?
Oh. it gets worse in summer.
This isn't summer.
You're right.
Would you like some water?
It's just $10.
Does it hurt?
Why would do you want to do
something like that?
Put yourself in a place like this?
I hate it here.
It's not so bad.
I have a very good nurse.
What were you trying to prove?
Was it...
Was it a test or something?
Hm?
They need to see proof of my
devotion.
If I didn't have my phone on me.
David. you would have bled out.
Mum!
He's resting.
Your life isn't just yours anymore.
Ivan. I can explain the Phelan
thing if you just let me.
No? OK.
Then can you at least tell me
why we're back where we started?
We're missing something.
I guess I'll just go over here
and look for the thing we missed.
Maybe we should try asking the bats
who killed Jonas.
Maybe they saw something.
We could just sit in the dark
and you could not tell me
what we missed...
or what you're thinking
or why you would point a gun
at your own head.
Is that what this is about?
Are we down here
so you can scare me some more?
Oh. look. Some dirt.
Is that what we're looking for?
Are we looking for dirt?
Because I can see a lot of it.
No opal here.
What!?
Ivan!
Through here.
I think I'm in Ada's place.
I think they're connected.
Turn that off.
What if it wasn't Jonas's opal?
What if he was stealing it?
From his sister.
What now?
Step outside. Ada.
Why didn't you tell us there's
a crawl space?
'Cause I don't know anything
about that.
Yeah.
Ada Torshack. you're under arrest
for obstruction of justice...
and under suspicion
for the murder of Jonas McGee.
Well. I'd better lock up. then.
Ada.
No. no. no. no. no.
Shit.
How can we help you. Robbie?
Did you hear the news?
May he rest in peace. What?
Kalingra went public.
Oh. it was a thing of bloody beauty.
Our beige whale finally breached.
unlocked the whole deal.
Breached?
Yeah. We got a backdoor entry onto
the NASDAQ. Detective.
The market's just closed.
I've been up all night.
Who was your beige whale?
Your investors from China?
No. Sadly. they fell through.
Oh. did they find other acting work?
Ah! Here she is!
Old moneybags herself.
Hi. auntie!
This is your beige whale?
Hey. Auntie Coll. Congratulations.
I knew you'd come around.
Maybe you can use the money
to turn those shit-catchers
into some grown-up pants.
See you at the iron ring.
Indeed. Indeed! Ah!
There's a memorial going on
for the sun burnt whale.
You know. Mayor Dougie.
May he rest in peace.
So you're done with Kalingra?
No. I've got a small parcel
under Founders Lock.
but I can just sit back now.
relax and watch Colleen dig herself
a big hole.
Oh. did you guys catch the killer?
Nice. Good work.
So I might head off and try
and get some sleep.
Any tips. Detective?
Just kidding.
Wanker.
Ada.
Not you. Him.
Also you.
Ada!
Kyle. you're on speaker.
You gotta let my mum go.
Kyle. stop!
Mum. you didn't do it.
Kyle! I did it.
I cut his head off.
Go! Drive!
Kyle...
you told us that Jonas was already
dead when you found him in the mine.
Yeah.
Yep.
And his head was attached
when you found him.
I...
I went down there
to catch him ratting from us.
I used the hole he dug.
But he was just lying there dead.
Head on.
Mm.
And then what happened?
I knew... I knew it was David
who did it.
I told you I heard them arguing
in Uncle Jonas's caravan.
Mm-hm.
He was threatening to expose David
for covering up Zig's death.
He wanted hush money for Elsie
and Bess for their medical bills.
I knew it was David who...
who'd shut him up.
and I knew he'd find a way
to get out of it too. you know.
I couldn't let him do that.
So I picked up the axe. and I...
and... and I cut his head off.
So you tried
to point us at David. right. Kyle?
With the head.
Matthew 11. verse 3.
Yeah. Mm-hm.
Yeah. like John the Baptist.
John the Baptist. Yeah.
Making someone look guilty isn't
the same as proving it. Kyle.
That's why you're in here
and David's not.
OK. Kyle. I have something
to show you.
These are your phone records.
See this one?
Last Friday. just after you were
released from the station here...
your first call was to your mum.
Ada's admitted to us
what you said to her on the phone.
But we'd like to hear
what she said to you.
Now. please. Kyle.
She...
She said no-one would ever believe
that I just walked in on him dead.
And she said...
She said...
She said I'd be the one to go
down for it. not David.
Mm-hm.
So she fixed it.
I need you to tell me how.
How did she fix it?
How did she fix it. Kyle?
She took the head...
to pin it on someone else
and buy us...
buy us some time
and make the trail messy.
OK. So when was
the last time you saw Jonas alive?
He came to see me.
I work at Kalingra.
I thought he was going to apologise
for being a rat.
but he was just sniffing around
for dirt.
But I didn't kill him.
That counts for something. yeah?
Oh. Kyle.
What you've done. Kyle.
is you've altered human remains
to pervert.
to manipulate the course of justice.
Yeah.
15 years. Kyle.
15 years
for butchering your uncle's body.
And for what?
We still don't know who killed him.
Sergeant.
Kyle. you come with me. please.
Take a seat. Luc.
Shouldn't take long.
Need you as a witness. Buchanan.
Fuck!
Carole?
Nell. bad news. The
results came back on the soil sample
that you found in McGee's ute.
What have we got?
Well. in layman's terms.
it's just regular dirt.
The same dirt
I pulled off McGee's clothes.
The man was practically marinated
in it.
But. yeah. it's. uh...
It's just dirt. I'm sorry.
Clothing.
He came to see me.
I work at Kalingra.
But he was just sniffing around
for dirt.
Dirt.
OK.
Nell?
Hey. pal.
I see you've found yourself a pet.
Well.
the opportunity presented itself.
Like you with Goran Horvat. Hm.
My senior partner
came clean with me
about avenging the death of his son.
It's great work.
Detective. Thank you.
That's not what I said.
You're here as a witness. Buchanan.
This is a ticket stub
to the Pooraka soccer club match
just over 12 months ago.
where Goran Horvat was executed
in the car park.
It proves that you and Horvat were
in the same place at the same time.
This is how we're doing it.
It was found in the inside pocket
of this jacket in your apartment.
Inadmissible.
Forensics have tested it
for gunshot residue.
Where's their report?
Yeah. I think I'd wash it.
Why wasn't the stub damaged?
It was in your hand.
and you put your hand in my pocket
when you went into my home without
a warrant.
Someone reported an animal
in distress.
Very sloppy. Nathan.
Very. very...
sloppy.
You lost your boy.
I get it.
I got two of my own now.
If anything ever happened
to them on my watch...
I couldn't...
And all this...
because your old man
killed Horvat's old man in Bukova?
Father to son. Father to son.
Father to son.
So it goes.
But it's Natalie...
that I feel sorry for.
I mean.
how could she possibly understand
the family
that she was marrying into?
Naturally. you'd blame yourself.
I mean. you lost everything.
You got pushed too far.
People understand that.
But the law is the law.
You're suspended.
Effective immediately.
pending an internal investigation
into the murder of Goran Horvat.
Ivan.
Gun and badge. Detective.
I d... I didn't... Ivan...
Ivan!
Buchanan.
PolAir leaves first thing
in the morning.
You'll be waiting on that tarmac
or I'll bring you back in cuffs.
Don't hang up. Ivan. listen to me.
I didn't...
Phelan messed with that recording.
You're a bad liar.
You know I can hear you through
the walls.
What?
Through the walls.
I can hear you talking to him
through the walls.
On the phone? Yes.
Oh. fuck. Ivan.
I'm not talking to Phelan.
Then who are you talking to?
Because you told me
that you have no-one.
I talk to a fake woman on
the phone.
There's this company
that designs software
that sounds like human voices.
and I speak to a fake voice
on the phone sometimes.
She's for intimacy.
This is why you called me? No.
Then why did you call me?
Because it's dirt. What?
Kyle said the last time he saw Jonas.
he was poking around Kalingra
for dirt.
Then Carole calls me. says
the same thing.
Says what?
The sample we found in McGee's ute.
it's just dirt. OK.
So why keep a tube of dirt
in your car?
You're not keeping it.
You're testing it.
Testing it for what?
I don't know yet.
I'm listening.
Nell.
Hello? Yes. Yes.
Shit. I gotta go.
Is this one of the mayor's drills.
Ray?
This is private property.
It's like he's still watching.
What's the matter. Ray?
You got something to hide?
What are you up to. girlie?
Nothin'.
Do I have to run you out
of town again?
What are you doing here?
I heard about David.
Is he gonna make it?
Well. he has to.
It's kind of a miracle. actually.
We just...
Hospitals are weird.
I can have a medevac on standby.
take you all to Adelaide tonight.
There are no strings.
Why? Why-why are you here. Robbie?
Why?
Because I like you. you weirdo.
And because I want to help.
But why?
Just be straight with me. OK?
What makes you think I haven't
been straight with you?
It's a feeling.
Well. facts aren't feelings.
Elsie.
Go on. Ask me anything you want.
OK. What is your middle name?
Lee. I was conceived in Lee's pub.
OK. What was your first injury?
I broke my arm jumping on
a trampoline.
How did your dad die?
It was a mining accident
at Cunnamulla.
He took a rock to the head
and he bled out in the dirt.
He died alone.
Oh. shit. Sorry.
You asked.
Yeah. and you answered.
I have to go.
I've got this tribute for the mayor.
I have to show up.
Can I please find you after?
Not if I find you first.
Mm...
Yes. Come find me.
Thank you.
You've reached Detective Ivan Lucic.
I can't make it to the phone.
Ivan. call me.
I'm following a lead.
I know you're suspended. but I...
I need... I...
Just call me back. OK?
Ray.
Find what you were looking for?
Oh-oh-oh.
Now. before you delete that.
put your hands up. Ray.
It's cosy in here. isn't it?
The mayor's little laundry room.
Give us a spin.
I had a hunch about this place.
of course. but you did the rest.
Thanks for that. Ray.
I appreciate it.
Don't let me interrupt.
Turn around.
Let's have a look.
Pull up Kalingra for me. Ray.
Tuesday. please.
Stop!
There's McGee's ute.
Hello. Jonas.
What happened to you?
You've reached Detective Ivan Lucic.
I can't make it to the phone.
Ivan. pick up. I figured it out.
I know who did it.
I have footage of the murder.
I know who killed Jonas McGee.
I saw all of it.
The mayor saw all of it. actually.
I locked Ray in his basement.
I left Ray watching footage
in his basement.
which maybe wasn't smart.
I don't have anyone else.
So I need you to answer the phone.
And I need you to still be here.
Pick up the phone!
Ivan!
Ivan.
That's not yours.
What happened to your ears?
The mayor.
Huh.
Thought you were dead.
No. Not yet anyway.
The iron ring.
The iron ring. Mm.
Hm.
I'm only the under card.
But you're the main event. mate.
Man Mountain. Hey.
Hey...
How's Nelly? Sorry - Nell.
She's good.
Is she?
One minute!
Mister. The Irishman.
Did Jonas ever talk to you
about Kalingra?
Eh?
Jonas. Talk to you about Kalingra?
Look. I'm trying to concentrate
here. mate.
Kalingra. Uh. yeah.
He brought me a sample to test
for him.
A soil sample? Yeah.
Why did he bring it here?
A geology minor
at the University of Aberdeen.
Thank you very much.
He did? Wow.
I didn't see that coming.
Nope. What did you find?
Uh... uh... uh... Igneous rock.
Uh. quartzite.
Clay loam. Salt.
No. uh. rare earth minerals?
No. mate. Zero. Zero.
Show time. Irish.
Hey. Frank.
No weapons.
Mrs Mayor's rules.
Who's fighting?
Behold...
the counterfeiter who thought he
could cheat this town.
One. two. three. four. five.
Tonight we honour my husband
and his legacy.
My Dougie built this place.
But I'm gonna make it...
LEGENDARY!
Now how about a big iron ring
welcome
to tonight's benefactors.
Colleen Delaney and Robbie Inglis.
You're just in time for the finale.
Introducing a detective...
Who gambled with
the wrong people...
up against the undefeated
people's champion.
Stan 'the Mountain Man' Honeywell!
Ivan! Ivan.
Nell. it's Robbie. Yes.
I have footage of him killing Jonas
with CCTV.
Go get him. They took my gun.
I'll buy you some time. What?
I'll buy you some time.
What? In there?
He'll kill you!
Make it quick. I'll try.
Place your bets!
Fight!
Stanley.
Stanley. Hey. Listen. Listen to me.
Ho!
Hey. Stanley. Stanley. listen to me.
It's about Jonas.
It's about Jonas. Your friend.
It's about your friend.
Listen. listen.
Well. cheers. Coll. To the future.
You mean my future?
I had my own geological surveys done
at Kalingra months ago.
There are no rare earth minerals.
But you already knew that.
What there is is lithium.
Trace amounts. Too small for
an amateur like you to notice.
But you know what that means.
Robbie.
Batteries.
The future.
So much effort to con me into buying
what you thought was a worthless
patch of dirt.
And you missed what was under it.
Stanley. listen.
I know who killed Jonas.
Robbie Inglis.
Uh...
Nice try
with your dirty little revenge play.
You think your father would be proud
of you?
I think he'd be glad he didn't
live to watch you fail him.
Ah!
Merv. get me out of this shithole.
Stanley!
Robbie!
Robert Inglis. you're under arrest
for the murder of Jonas McGee.
No back-up. You're brave.
No. Stanley! Stanley. no!
Stanley! Stanley. look at me!
Look at me.
Let him go! No!
Let go! No!
Stanley. you will go back to us.
You will go right back to prison.
I can't keep you out of prison.
You're gonna kill him! Let him go!
He killed my friend.
I can arrest him. I can arrest him.
I can put him away.
I can fix it if you let go.
You can trust me.
Whose funeral?
Do you always ask questions
you know the answer to. David?
Don't you think it's time
to let go now. Detective?
Ivan...
Ivan!
How'd you go?
Good.
♪ I'm a rambler
♪ Lord. I'm a gambler
♪ I'm a long way from my home
♪ If them people. they don't like me
♪ Lord. they can leave me alone
♪ It's dark. and Lord. it's raining
♪ And the moon gives no light
♪ My pony
♪ She won't travel
♪ This dark road at night... ♪
There's a sky full of lawyers
winging their way to us. Detective.
We both know that I'll be out
of here by lunchtime.
Mind if I join you. Robbie?
Hm.
We've got time-stamped CCTV footage
of you strangling Jonas McGee
to death.
Was he trying to stop you
from scamming Delaney.
or did he just want money?
Have you ever wondered
what it feels like to stand
in front of the person
who stole everything you care about?
At times.
Mm.
I knew I liked you.
I think you're gonna like it.
What's that?
The quiet.
Can you feel it?
Busy morning. Be right with you.
folks.
Good luck. Gary.
♪ Used to have me
for a little sweetheart... ♪
You are
enough. You are a born leader.
You know how to talk to any woman.
Yeah. just through here. mate.
-Here she is.
-Ah. it's the Breeze master 2000.
Yeah.
Did you give it a hit?
Many. Dazzler.
Yeah. he gave it a hit.
Good.
You're good at this. Detective.
Thanks.
I'm sorry about Phelan.
I hope everything works out for you.
Ivan.
It's 'Ee-vahn'.
What!?
My name.
It's 'Ee-vahn'.
OK.
Why didn't you just tell me that?
You never asked.
You never asked me.
What?
If I did it.
No.
Good.
♪ Many times I've tried to tell you
♪ Many times I've cried alone
♪ Always I'm surprised how well
♪ You've cut my feelings to the bone
♪ Don't wanna leave you. really
♪ I've invested too much time
♪ To give you up that easy
♪ To the doubts
that complicate your mind
♪ We belong to the light
We belong to the thunder
♪ We belong to the sound of the
words we've both fallen under
♪ Whatever we deny or embrace
♪ For worse or for better
♪ We belong. we belong.
we belong together
♪ Maybe it's a sign of weakness
♪ When I don't know what to say
♪ Maybe I just wouldn't know
what to do with my strength anyway
♪ Have we become a habit?
♪ Do we distort the facts?
♪ Now there's no looking forward
♪ Now there's no turning back
♪ When you say we belong to the
light. we belong to the...
'Ee-vahn'.
Do you mind if I call you 'Ee-vahn'?
♪ I see your face everywhere
♪ Still you say we belong
to the light
♪ We belong to the thunder
♪ We belong to the sound of the
words we've both fallen under
♪ Whatever we deny or embrace
♪ For worse or for better
♪ We belong
♪ We belong. we belong together... ♪
Captions by Red Bee Media